Okay. So let's see a full example of how the server and client-side can work together.
让我们看一个客户端和服务器端协同工作的例子
I'm going to start my server using the command node and then the name of
我使用 node L3Server.js
my file server which is L3Server.js,
启动服务器
and then I see it's up and running.
看 运行起来了
Now, here on the server code,
在服务器端代码中
we've done a simple post request which uses two arguments.
调用 post 设置路由 该方法需要两个参数
The first being the URL you want to use.
第一个参数是 URL
Our path is called addMovie because we want to create
这里使用 addMovie 因为我们想提供一个
an API where we add a movie and give it a score on a scale of 1-5.
用来添加影片的 API 并且在 1-5 之间为其打分
Here, addMovie is going to take the information we
在 addMovie 函数中 通过
get from request.body which is what we're really interested in.
req.body 获取请求数据
We want the body of our post request and we're going to push it into
我们从 POST 请求中获取数据并把它保存在数组中
our data array up here so that will have access to it from anywhere within our app.
这样就可以在应用的其他地方拿到它
But let's take a look on the client-side.
让我们再看一下客户端
This should look familiar by this point.
这些代码现在看起来应该很熟了
You see, we have our method post,
我们指定请求类型为 POST
we've made sure that JSON is all lined up,
使用 JSON 传输数据
and then we're going to call our function postData.
然后调用 postData 函数
We're going to pass in the path which is addMovie,
为其传入路径 addMovie
and then we're going to pass in some information that we want to test out to
和用来测试的数据
see if we can post this information to our app's data.
看看是否可以向应用发送 POST 请求
For our test, we're going to use the movie 'The Matrix' and a score five out of five,
让我们用影片 黑客帝国 并且满分 5 分 来测试
which I may remind you is a perfect score,
这是我最喜欢的一部电影
and we'll see if our app can grab it.
让我们看看服务器端是否能拿到这一数据
So here, if we go into the browser and refresh our browser, we see boom.
刷新浏览器
We've gotten movie 'The Matrix' Score 5 in our browser,
我们看到了 黑客帝国 和 5 分的评分
and not only that because we're doing client-side and server-side,
由于服务器端和客户端都是我们实现的
here on our server if you look in the terminal,
观察服务器终端
you can see that we've also got a whole data object.
我们得到了同样的数据
That's coming from this line of code which says
在使用 push 存储数据后 我们使用这一行
after we push the information we want into
console.log(data)
data console.log or apps data which we now have movie 'The Matrix' Score 5.
将它打印出来 得到了 5 分的 黑客帝国
Okay. Let's try another example.
让我们再举一例
What if we wanted to add another movie and another score to our app endpoint?
假设我们要添加另一部电影
We'll call our postData function again,
再次调用 postData 函数
and then we'll pass in the same URL because we want to addMovie.
使用同样的 URL 添加影片
Now, we're going to pass in the data in the form of an object.
然后传入影片信息
So we'll make our object by saying movie.
创建 movie 对象
What's another great movie?
还有什么好片子呢？
'Pitch Perfect,' that'll do.
Pitch Perfect
Then for score, I'm tempted to give it a five,
我个人倾向给打 5 分
but we can't give every movie a five,
但是总不能所有影片都打 5 分吧
so we'll go 4.5, nearly perfect.
给个 4.5 吧
Now, when we save our new code,
保存代码
we should go to our app,
回到应用
we'll refresh, and boom.
刷新
We see this time, we got 'Pitch Perfect' with a score of
我们看到了 Pitch Perfect 4.5 分
4.5 and that's in the browser which is our client-side code.
这是客户端代码
But if we go over to our server in the terminal,
如果回到服务器端 观察终端
we can see that our data object now holds the matrix with
会发现打印出 黑客帝国 5 分
a score of five and Pitch Perfect with a score of 4.5.
Pitch Perfect 4.5 分
If we look in the terminal from our server code,
我们观察服务器端终端
we can now see that all the data has been saved
会发现所有数据都被保存下来
into our data object and it's being given back to us here.
并且在终端打印出来
We can see movie 'The Matrix Score 5,' movie 'Pitch Perfect' score is 4.5.
我们可以看到 黑客帝国 5 分 Pitch Perfect 4.5 分
So that's how we work together with the server and
这就是客户端和服务器端
the client-side to bring together our routes and our requests.最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
是如何一起工作的。最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6